Reading Tosk
Iqbaluit
The Frozen Town
The reporter Beth Allen arrived in a northern community called Iqbaluit in Nunavut.
Nunavut was created in 1999 as a special area for Inuit people.
Its name means "Our Land" in their language.
It is in the farthest northeastern area of Canada,
north of the Arctic Circle(北极圈),
and is very cold - the average winter temperature in Nunavut is 35 degrees below zero.
Beth said, "I knew it would be cold in January,
but not this cold!
Maybe there is a dog sled (雪橇) that can take me into town." The quiet man who
had been on the plane
with her said, "I’ll take you into town,
but I don’t have a dog sled.
Most people only use the dogs for competitions.
My name is Simon and I am Inuit," he said.
I think it’s too far north here for holidays but more and more tourists are coming.
They like ice fishing and photographing polar bears.
I stay as far away from polar bears as possible.
I like my warm office and my warm house." Beth asked, "
What do you do in an office?
Don’t you hunt animals for a living?
My grandfather would live in ice houses when he hunted in winter,
but not so many people do that now.
The old men used to make one in a few hours.
Beth said, "Why is it so dark?
It’s the middle of the day!" Simon replied, "
It’s dark in the day because we are so far north.
You should come in June.
The sun shines all night in the north then.
That’s why it’s called ’The Land of the Midnight Sun’."
There were people on the streets
and snowmobiles everywhere.
There were even a few dog teams.